A Guide to the Fields M. Young Papers 1881-1923
Digital Library and Archive, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Fields M. Young Papers 1881-1923
Digital Library and Archive, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Ms85-018
2 containers; 0.7 cu. ft.
Papers of a Grayson County, Virginia merchant. Includes correspondence relating to personal and financial matters, as well as store business; advertising materials from various manufacturers and wholesalers; financial records; folders relating to the Grayson County School Board and Walter R. Hardin; and printed materials.
Donor
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Fields M. Young Papers were donated to the Digital Library and Archives in 1985.
Biographical/Historical Information
Fields M. Young, Grayson County merchant, was born in Edgewater (Grayson County), Virginia in 1846. The son of Ezekiel and Evaline McMillan Young, Fields Young remained in Grayson County and operated a general store and mill there. He also served as Edgewater postmaster and as a member of the Grayson County School Board for several years. He and his wife, Mary E. Waugh Young, had three children, two of whom (James and Virginia) died young. Another daughter, Mattie, grew to adulthood and married Walter R. Hardin, president of the Roanoke Notion Company, a wholesale business. Fields Young died in 1928.
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains the papers of Fields M. Young, a Grayson County, Virginia merchant and miller. The collection includes such materials as correspondence, financial records, and printed materials.
Young's correspondence has been divided into two categories: personal and store correspondence. While the personal correspondence includes many letters from friends and family members, much of it relates to Young's personal financial affairs and investments. A few letters also relate to Young's political interests, including a letter from Senator Claude Swanson. The personal correspondence contains a large number of letters from his son-in-law, Walter R. Hardin, and friend and Marion National Bank cashier, T. E. King. The store correspondence includes mostly letters from manufacturers and wholesalers regarding business proposals and accounts. It also contains a few letters from local customers regarding their accounts and orders for goods. Both the personal and store correspondence are arranged alphabetically by name of sender (either individual or company).
Complementing the store correspondence is a large group of advertising matter from various wholesalers and retailers. The collection includes flyers, catalogs, prices lists, complimentary ink blotters, seed samples, etc. The advertising matter is arranged alphabetically by company name.
Among Young's financial records are personal checks, receipts and account statements.
Young's service on the Grayson County School Board is represented in a small collection of correspondence and printed materials relating to teaching positions and school supplies.
The collection also includes a folder relating to Young's son-in-law, Walter R. Hardin, president of the Roanoke Notion Company, a wholesale business. Much of this material consists of letters addressed to Hardin in Sparta, North Carolina, regarding the company's daily transactions.
Among the printed materials are flyers and brochures for the 1922 senatorial campaigns of Westmoreland Davis and Claude A. Swanson. Also included are materials on public health issues.
A folder of general materials completes the collection and includes an unidentified tintype (possibly of Mary E. Waugh Young).
Contents List
- Personal correspondence 1894-1923
  - A-G (Box-folder 1-1)
  - H-J (Box-folder 1-2)
  - K (Box-folder 1-3)
  - L-R (Box-folder 1-4)
  - S-Z, unidentified (Box-folder 1-5)
- Store correspondence 1883-1923
  - A-J (Box-folder 1-6)
  - K-R (Box-folder 1-7)
  - S-Z (Box-folder 1-8)
- Advertising matter 1883-1923
  - A-E (Box-folder 1-9)
  - F-K (Box-folder 1-10)
  - L-Q (Box-folder 1-11)
  - R-S (Box-folder 1-12)
  - T-Z (Box-folder 1-13)
- Personal checks 1892-1916 (Box-folder 2-1)
- Other financial records 1881-1923 (Box-folder 2-2)
- Grayson County School Board 1891-1922, n.d. (Box-folder 2-3)
- Walter R. Hardin 1917-1922 (Box-folder 2-4)
- Printed materials 1917-1922, n.d. (Box-folder 2-5)
- General materials 1897-1917, n.d. (Box-folder 2-6)